gamepro.com 2011-06-30

# Online Privacy Statement | GamePro Media - 20 Years of Making Games Fun

## About Ad Choices 

**About Our Advertising**

GamePro Media strives to deliver the most relevant content and ads to our readers. The advertising included on our site enables us to deliver the reporting resources required to create the high-quality journalism, research and analysis our audience expects from us.

Advertisements displayed on this site may be based on the content of pages you view or may be delivered by third parties and tailored to your interests. These third parties may also collect anonymous, non-personally identifiable information through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies about your online activities on this site, in order to deliver advertisements that are relevant to your interests.

**Our Policies**

GamePro Media follows the Self Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral advertising. More information on the principles, and information and choices about interest-based advertising, can be found at the [Self Regulatory Program](http://www.aboutads.info/) site, including links to opt-out from services that deliver online behavioral ads.

For additional information on cookies, web beacons and our collection and use of information, please read our Privacy Policy below.

## Online Privacy Policy

The GamePro Media, Inc. Web sites (" Sites") and associated sites are maintained by, GamePro Media, Inc., 501 2nd Street, San Francisco, CA 94107. The GPM Sites include, but are not limited to, GameProMedia.com, GamePro.com, GameProLabs.com, Games.net, GamerHelp.com, GameDownloads.com, GameStar.com, Blogfaction.com, and GameProFamily.com.

GamePro Media collects personally identifying information and data about individuals, their company, and the companies demographics "personally identifying information and data" including (i) when you provide information to GamePro Media, such as when you register or sign up for any of our products such as publications, subscriptions, e-mails, contests, newsletters, memberships, RSS Feeds, webcasts, White Papers, online seminars, conferences and other communications with GamePro Media (ii) when you register or sign up on the GPM Sites or when you register for any other IDG Publishing Network products individually or through "auto register", your information will be known to GamePro Media and (iii) from time to time we may add other information that we collect from third party sources to enhance the information that you provided to GamePro Media.

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by GamePro Media. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. GamePro Media reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifying information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website. GamePro Media or one of our IDG affiliated companies, or third party partners may place a "cookie" in the browser files of a user's computer. The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifying information, except when such information has been supplied by a subscriber or registered user.

If you have registered with GamePro Media, the information in your "cookie" is used to provide a more personalized experience on the GPM Sites.

If you haven't registered with our site, we may place a cookie on your system to help provide a more personalized experience on the GPM Sites. This cookie identifies you as a unique user by means of a tracking ID. However, if you have not registered on our site, we cannot link that user ID with personal identifying information and data about you such as your name or e-mail address.

Other cookies without personally identifying information and data are used to enable GamePro Media to manage the banner advertisements presented or personalized information to the user.

Browsers or third-party software can allow you to block the use of cookies while you surf our site. Or, you can use third-party "anonymizer" services to mask information in your cookies, or even general data such as your IP address. In such cases you would not be able to take advantage of most of the personalization services offered by the GPM Sites.

For more information about cookies, head to Computerworld's Cookies QuickStudy.

The aggregated information we collect is used for a number of purposes including the following purposes:

  * To improve the content and design of the GPM Sites.
  * To enable our audit bureau to verify our claims of traffic to the GPM Sites.
  * To help advertisers, potential advertisers or marketers assess the suitability of the site for their ad campaigns. as clear GIFs, also known as pixel tags, provided by our ad-serving company to help manage online advertising. These clear GIFS let our ad-serving company recognize a browser's cookie when a user visits our site. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable (It does not include your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address). For more information about our ad-serving company or for your choices about not having this anonymous information used, please visit www.doubleclick.net.
  * GamePro Media has contracted with DoubleClick to serve all advertising on the GPM Sites, both on the GPM Sites themselves and through its e-mail newsletters. When DoubleClick is serving ads, it recognizes certain types of non-personally identifiable information, such as a user's IP address, browser version or type, operating system, service provider and time zone. DoubleClick also uses cookies to note the general content of the sites that users visit over time in order to serve ads on this site and other sites. Any pages a user calls up on the GPM Sites aren't connected with personally identifiable information collected either at the GPM Sites or elsewhere. For more details about the non-personally identifiable information DoubleClick collects and the opportunity to opt out of such data collection, please visit www.doubleclick.net/privacy_policy/ . We use web metric vendors to gather information to help us understand how users utilize our websites and other electronic products.
  * We may create and use aggregate customer data to understand more about the interests of our customers and may use the data to offer goods and services we believe may be of interest to our customers, on behalf of GamePro Media or select organizations.

Postal addresses, and other personally identifying information and data will be used to promote GamePro Media and IDG products and services, and may be rented and/or licensed to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the personal identifying information and data are rented and/or licensed for use and the users are required to target their offers carefully.

Telephone numbers of GamePro Media print subscribers are used by GamePro Media to collect re-qualification data and may be used by GamePro Media, IDG and other IDG companies, affiliates and it's advertisers for promotional purposes. GamePro Media may rent and/or license for use phone numbers to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the numbers are rented required renters and/or licensed for use are required to target their offers carefully.

Fax numbers of GamePro Media print subscribers are used by GamePro Media to collect re-qualification data and may be used for surveys for GamePro Media and third parties. Except as set forth in this policy no fax numbers are rented and/or licensed to outside firms.

E-mail addresses of GamePro Media print subscribers are used for re-qualification or renewal purposes. These e-mail addresses may also be used to collect feedback by members of our editorial or research team, to promote GamePro Media and IDG products and services, and they may be rented to other firms and/or licensed for promotional purposes. We allow users to "opt-out" of receiving e-mail from outside firms and/or GamePro Media, Inc. and its sister IDG companies when e-mail information is collected and with each e-mail use of the user's address. If a user does not choose to "opt-out" at the time the e-mail address is collected, the address may be used by GamePro Media, its sister IDG Companies or rented and/or licensed for use to outside firms. Offers for which the e-mail address is rented and/or licensed for use require the users to target their offers carefully.

We allow users to "opt-out" of receiving E-mail from outside firms and/or GamePro Media, Inc. and its sister IDG companies when E-Mail information is collected and with each E-mail use of the user's address. If a user does not respond to the questions concerning how we may use their e-mail address at the time the e-mail address is collected, the address may be used by GamePro Media, its sister IDG companies or rented and/or licensed to outside firms. Users who later decide they want to change their preferences may do so by sending an e-mail to updatelists@idg-entertainment.com.

Personal identifying information submitted on portions of our site developed with outside third parties may be shared with those third parties, and the information will be governed by those parties' privacy policies as well as GamePro Media's. GamePro Media, nor any of its parent companies or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates do not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of such third parties.

GamePro Media users should be aware that when they disclose personal identifying information (e.g., user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and E-mail address) in discussion forums, chat rooms or other areas that are publicly accessible by others, that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties. GamePro Media nor its parent company or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates are not responsible for any information that you provide in the above areas. In the event that the ownership of GamePro Media or any of its products are sold or transferred all lists and data which contains personally identifying information and data including for example user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and e-mail address, will be transferred to the new owner.

## Print Subscriber and "Auto Register" Privacy Policy"

GamePro Media collects personally identifying information and data about individuals their company and the company's demographics ("personally identifying information and data") (i) when you provide information to GamePro Media, such as when you register or sign up for any of our products such as publications, subscriptions, RSS Feeds, web casts, White Papers, online seminars, conferences emails, contests, newsletters, memberships and other communications with GamePro Media. (ii) when you register or sign up on the GPM Site(s) or when you register for any other IDG Publishing Network products individually or through "auto register", your information your information will be known to GamePro Media and (iii) from time to time we may add other information that we collect from third party sources to enhance the information that you provided to GamePro Media.

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by GamePro Media. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. GamePro Media reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifying information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website.

Subscribers and applicants for GamePro Media Print subscriptions are asked to complete a questionnaire with personally identifying information and demographics. The data is used in a number of ways including the following:

  * To improve the content of GamePro Media.
  * To notify subscribers about re-qualification and renewal.
  * Used by us for marketing GamePro Media products and services.
  * Used by our audit bureau to verify cumulative demographic statistics.
  * Used by GamePro Media, IDG, its subsidiaries and its affiliates and IDC for research surveys.
  * Used by Editorial for consultation with readers.

Postal addresses, and other personally identifying information and data will be used to promote GamePro Media and IDG products and services, and may be rented and/or licensed to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the names are rented and/or licensed for use and the users are required to target their offers carefully.

Telephone numbers of GamePro Media print subscribers are used by GamePro Media to collect re-qualification data and may be used by GamePro Media, IDG, its subsidiaries and affiliates, their advertisers for promotional purposes. GamePro Media may rent and/or license for use telephone numbers to selected outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the telephone numbers are rented and/or licensed for use require users to target their offers carefully.

Fax numbers of GamePro Media print subscribers are used by GamePro Media to collect re-qualification data and may be used for surveys for GamePro Media, IDG and its affiliates and third parties. Except as set forth in this policy, no fax numbers are rented and/or licensed to outside firms.

E-mail addresses of GamePro Media print subscribers are used for re-qualification or renewal purposes. These e-mail addresses may also be used to collect feedback from subscribers by members of our editorial or research team, to promote GamePro Media and IDG products and services, and they may be rented and/or licensed to other firms for promotional purposes. We allow users to "opt-out" of receiving e-mail from outside firms and/or GamePro Media, Inc. and its sister IDG Companies when e-mail information is collected and with each e-mail use of the user's address. If a user does not "opt-out" at the time the e-mail address is collected, the address may be used by GamePro Media, its sister IDG Companies or rented and/or licensed to outside firms. Offers for which the e-mail address is rented and/or licensed for use require the users to target their offers carefully.

In the event that the ownership of GamePro Media or any of its products are sold the all lists and data which contains personally identifying information and data including for example user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and e-mail address, will be transferred to the new owner.

Print Subscribers or applicants who do not want their names used in any of the above ways may write and ask to be removed from the promotion list. Requests should be sent to:

**GamePro Media, Inc.**  
P.O. Box 3500  
Northbrook, IL 60065-3500  

## IDG Publishing Network Online Registration Privacy Policy

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by the IDG Publishing Network. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. The IDG Publishing Network reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifiable information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website.

## About the IDG Publishing Network

The International Data Group, Inc. (IDG) family of on-line and print publications consists of hundreds of award-winning titles including Bio-IT World, CIO, CSO, Darwin, InfoWorld, Game Pro, Network World, Macworld and PC World. The IDG Publishing Network is a growing collection of IDG web sites that presently includes bio-itworld.com, cio.com, csoonline.com, GamePro.com, Games.net, GamerHelp.com, GameDownloads.com, Gamestar.com, Blogfaction.com, darwinmag.com, health-itworld.com, infoworld.com, nwfusion.com, macworld.com, maccentral.com, and pcworld.com. A complete listing is available at www.idg.com.

To access restricted content on any IDG Publishing Network web site you must be a member of the IDG Publishing Network. To become a member of the IDG Publishing Network, you need to provide certain information about yourself. Any of the IDG Publishing Network sites may use this identifying information for internal analytical and business development purposes and, with your permission, to send you email. However, other forms of communication, including postal mail, may be directed to you pursuant to the site's specific privacy policy, as may be updated from time to time.

You can update or change the identifying information you provided during registration at any time by clicking the link to access your IDG Publishing Network profile. The profile can be accessed from any IDG Publishing Network site. You also at any time may request not to receive further email from the editor and publisher of an IDG Publishing Network site or from third parties they approve by updating your answers to the two permission questions on your IDG Publishing Network profile on the given site. You can also "opt-out" of receiving further email by clinking the appropriate links that appear at the bottom of any email you receive. If you do not want to receive other types of communication, including as applicable, postal mail, from the editor and publisher of the site, please refer to the site's privacy policy for the procedure to follow.

The IDG Publishing Network is intended for individuals over the age of 13 years old. Personal information may not be provided by anyone under 13 years of age. Further no one under 13 years old may participate in the forums or chat rooms or any other areas where public discussions may take place. In addition no one under that age of 18 may conduct any transactions for the purposes or purchasing or selling any items. Parents should be sure that their children are not conducting any of the above activities on the IDG Publishing Network.

If you have any questions or comments regarding the IDG Publishing Network or its use of information please send email to IDGNetwork@idg.com or write to us at IDG Publishing Network, 3 Post Office Square, Boston, MA 02109.

Last updated: August 6, 2009.

## Correct/Update

To change or modify information previously provided, users can send an email to [updatelists@gamepromedia.com](mailto:updatelists@gamepromedia.com).

If you have any questions about this Statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, you can contact:

GamePro Media  
Customer Service Department  
501 2nd Street, Suite 500  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
Email: privacy@gamepro.com
